Guide to the Milton Terris Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Milton Terris papers
1944-1968
MS 809
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist of reports, minutes of meetings, correspondence, printed matter and other papers largely related to the American Public Health Association and particularly its Committee for the Creation of a Medical Care Section. These papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Terris, Milton, 1915-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Arthur J. Viseltear, 1977.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of reports, minutes of meetings, correspondence, printed matter and other papers largely related to the American Public Health Association and particularly its Committee for the Creation of a Medical Care Section. These papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Medicine; Public health; Physicians; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Terris, Milton, 1915-; American Public Health Association
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, 1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee for the Creation of a Medical Care Section in the American Public Health Association: correspondence, meeting agenda, petition, policy statements, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Medical Care Subcommittee of the A.P.H.A.: minutes, policy statements, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of the meeting of the governing council, A.P.H.A., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Reprints of statements made by the A.P.H.A., 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Writings by Milton Terris, 1944-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1984 Dec. Addition
  - Milton Terris' acceptance speech for A. P. H. A.'s Sedgwick Memorial Medal, with program, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)